{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Theodore Roosevelt","incorrectAnswers":["Edward the Confessor","Edward Elgar","Ted Nugent"],"question":"After which famous person in history was the teddy bear named?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Saffron","incorrectAnswers":["Cloves","Cinnamon","Pepper"],"question":"What is the world's most expensive spice by weight?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Buz Aldrin","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Armstrong","Michael Collins","John Glenn"],"question":"Who was the second person to set foot on the moon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Indonesia","incorrectAnswers":["Cote d'Ivoire","Cameroon","Bosnia and Herzegovina"],"question":"Jakarta is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Cruella de Vil","incorrectAnswers":["Maleficent","Ursula","Scar"],"question":"Which Disney villainess has a song with the line \"If she doesn't scare you, no evil thing will\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Quito","incorrectAnswers":["Cusco","Lima","Cordoba"],"question":"What is the capital of Ecuador?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Raphael","incorrectAnswers":["Henri Matisse","Jan van Eyck","Diego Rivera"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Triumph of Galatea\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Isaac Asimov","incorrectAnswers":["Ursula K. Le Guin","Philip K. Dick","Stephen King"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Foundation series'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Faster Than Light","incorrectAnswers":["Far Telescopic Light","Feasible To Live","Field Transform Loop"],"question":"In space talk, what do the initials FTL stand for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lyon","incorrectAnswers":["Berlin","Copenhagen","Rotterdam"],"question":"Which of these cities is in France?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Oasis","incorrectAnswers":["Goldfrapp","Kaiser Chiefs","Jethro Tull"],"question":"Which band includes 'Liam Gallagher'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Joseph Conrad","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Great Expectations'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Netherlands","incorrectAnswers":["Poland","Portugal","Greece"],"question":"From 1795-1806, which country was briefly known as the Batavian Republic?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Grapes","incorrectAnswers":["Apples","Oranges","Bananas"],"question":"Which fruit comes in Tokay and Emperor varieties?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["The Middle East","Central America","North America"],"question":"Where in the world are yams originally from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cricket","incorrectAnswers":["Hockey","Table tennis","Cycling"],"question":"With which sport is Sachin Tendulkar associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A school","incorrectAnswers":["A herd","A murder","A murmuration"],"question":"What is the word for a group of whales?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Detroit Red Wings","incorrectAnswers":["Detroit Football","Detroit Bucks","Detroit Canucks"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in Detroit?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Insulin","incorrectAnswers":["Oxytocin","Adrenaline","Testosterone"],"question":"Which pancreatic hormone works to lower glucose levels in the blood?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Yellow Brick Road","incorrectAnswers":["The Red Brick Road","The Emerald Road","The Sapphire Road"],"question":"What did Dorothy and her friends walk down in The Wizard of Oz?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nur-Sultan","incorrectAnswers":["Gitega","Asmara","Tashkent"],"question":"What is the capital city of Kazakhstan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tubular pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Strand pasta","Soup pasta","Ribbon pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is cavatappi?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Benign","incorrectAnswers":["Malignant","Corotid","Oncolosant"],"question":"A non-cancerous tumor is said to be what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Nicole Kidman","incorrectAnswers":["Natalie Portman","Kate Winslet","Maggie Smith"],"question":"Which actress has featured in films including Moulin Rouge! and Aquaman?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Honda","incorrectAnswers":["Mazda","Jaguar","Aston Martin"],"question":"Which motoring brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'The Power of Dreams'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kazan","incorrectAnswers":["Düsseldorf","Cologne","Vienna"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Russia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Volleyball","Cricket","Cycling"],"question":"With which sport is Jesse Owens associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kelly Clarkson","incorrectAnswers":["Carrie Underwood","Jennifer Hudson","Adam Lambert"],"question":"Who won the first season of American Idol?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The dent on the base ","incorrectAnswers":["The neck","The curve leading to the neck","The foil covering the cork"],"question":"What, on a bottle of wine, is the punt?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Silver","incorrectAnswers":["Iron","Titanium","Zinc"],"question":"Electrum is a natural alloy of gold and what other metal?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Foal","incorrectAnswers":["A Cria","A Bunny","A Lamb"],"question":"What is the word for a young mule?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Eminem","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Drake","Ludacris"],"question":"Which American rapper, producer and actor released the studio album 'Encore'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Burj Khalifa","incorrectAnswers":["Shanghai Tower","Taipei 101","Empire State Building"],"question":"What is the tallest building in the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hematite","incorrectAnswers":["Chloroform","Table Salt","Heavy water"],"question":"What is iron oxide commonly known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Detroit","incorrectAnswers":["Boston","New York","Los Angeles"],"question":"What US city's name means 'straits' or 'channel'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hot","incorrectAnswers":["Wet","Windy","Dark"],"question":"In what conditions do thermophilous plants thrive?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Las Vegas","incorrectAnswers":["Los Angeles","Lansing","Louisiana"],"question":"Which city is represented by the airport code LAS?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Advancement Through Technology","incorrectAnswers":["Grace, Space, Pace.","There is no substitute","Think Small"],"question":"What is the marketing slogan of Audi?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Baking Soda","incorrectAnswers":["Bleach","Table Salt","Dolomite"],"question":"What is the common name for sodium bicarbonate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Blackberry and raspberry","incorrectAnswers":["Blueberry and Strawberry","Gooseberry and Raspberry","Strawberry and Gooseberry"],"question":"A tayberry is a cross between which two fruits?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Leonardo da Vinci","incorrectAnswers":["Pierre-Auguste Renoir","Diego Velázquez","Pieter Bruegel the Elder"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Mona Lisa\"","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Harry Truman","incorrectAnswers":["Lyndon Johnson","Dwight Eisenhower","Richard Nixon"],"question":"Who Was President Of The USA In 1952? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Calvin Coolidge","incorrectAnswers":["Martin Van Buren ","Grover Cleveland","Rutherford B. Hayes"],"question":"Who was the 30th president of the USA, in term during the period 1923–1929?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Hawaii","incorrectAnswers":["Alaska","Puerto Rico","New Mexico"],"question":"What Became America's 50th State On August 21st 1959?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Peru","incorrectAnswers":["Zimbabwe","Brazil","Venezuela"],"question":"Where is Machu Picchu?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Race","incorrectAnswers":["Parasites","Ethics","Rocks"],"question":"What is Ethnology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Liberia","incorrectAnswers":["Cote d'Ivoire","Nepal","Mauritania"],"question":"Monrovia is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used as an ingredient in baking.","incorrectAnswers":["It is used in liquid fertilizers, potassium soaps and detergents.","It is used in laundry detergent.","It is used to relieve pain."],"question":"What is the chemical sodium bicarbonate often used for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"An Invisibility Cloak","incorrectAnswers":["A Magic Bean","A Stone of Immortality","A Wand"],"question":"What did Harry Potter get for Christmas in his first semester at Hogwarts School?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Saruman","incorrectAnswers":["Gandalf","Radagast","Merlin"],"question":"Which wizard was portrayed by Christopher Lee in The Lord Of The Rings?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The White House","incorrectAnswers":["The Louvre","Buckingham Palace","The Vatican"],"question":"In which iconic building is \"The Yellow Oval Room\" located?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Isaac Asimov","incorrectAnswers":["Ursula K. Le Guin","Philip K. Dick","Stephen King"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Foundation and Empire'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Venezuela","incorrectAnswers":["USA","Brazil","France"],"question":"What was the first country to abolish the death penalty in the 19th century?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bad Boys","incorrectAnswers":["Men in Black","Independence Day","Wild Wild West"],"question":"What was the name of the popular '90s police film starring Will Smith and Martin Lawrence?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Jackson","Ringo Starr","Elvis Presley"],"question":"Which Singer Starred In The Title Role Of The Film 'Merry Christmas Mr Lawrence''?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A Star Is Born","incorrectAnswers":["Grease","The Sound of Music","Rocky Horror Picture Show"],"question":"Barbra Streisand and Kris Kristofferson both won Golden Globe awards for their roles in what 1976 musical remake?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I’m the guy who does his job. You must be the other guy.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"You motorboatin’ son of a b****!\"","\"I am big! It's the pictures that got small.\"","\"I'm gonna make him an offer he can't refuse.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Departed'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Allah","incorrectAnswers":["Mohammed","Yaweh","Jehovah"],"question":"What is God called in the Muslim faith?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Walk This Way ","incorrectAnswers":["I Don't Want To Miss A Thing","Sweet Emotion","Last Child"],"question":"Which Aerosmith song was re-made by Run D.M.C.?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Uruguay","incorrectAnswers":["South Africa","Germany","Mexico"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1930 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Tabard","incorrectAnswers":["The King's Head","The Red Lion","The Altar"],"question":"In \"The Canterbury Tales\", at which tavern do the story tellers assemble?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Napoleonic War","incorrectAnswers":["World War II","Vietnam War","Korean War"],"question":"Which of these wars took place before World War I?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Venezuela","incorrectAnswers":["Trinidad and Tobago","Guyana","Colombia"],"question":"What country's capital is Caracas?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"nasal","incorrectAnswers":["fricative","affricative","plosive"],"question":"In phonetics, the m in 'mother' is an example of what kind of sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Under the Volcano","incorrectAnswers":["Nine Stories","Blood Meridian","Pale Fire"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Geoffrey Firmin'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Anelli","incorrectAnswers":["Gomiti","Penne","Ravioli"],"question":"Which pasta's name means 'Rings'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bulgaria","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","China","Kyrgyzstan"],"question":"Which of these countries has white on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Haiti","incorrectAnswers":["Egypt","Cuba","Chile"],"question":"What is the only state in history to have been established by a slave revolt?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Yanka Kupala","incorrectAnswers":["Nikolai Gogol","Vladimir Nabokov","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'On Paths of Life'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"All I Want For Christmas Is You\" by Mariah Carey","incorrectAnswers":["\"Jumpin', Jumpin'\" by Destiny's Child","\"American Pie\" by Don McLean","\"Let it Be\" by the Beatles"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"I don't want a lot for Christmas, there is just one thing I need.\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Hand","incorrectAnswers":["Foot","Swarm","Flock"],"question":"What is the name for a cluster or bunch of bananas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Evanescence","incorrectAnswers":["The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American alternative metal band released the studio album 'The Open Door'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Chemist who had a leading impact on the chemical revolution.","incorrectAnswers":["Improved the Newcomen steam engine creating an efficient steam engine.","King of Macedonia and military leader.","Liberator of Latin American countries."],"question":"Which of the following describes Antoine Laurent Lavoisier?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Computer Mouse","incorrectAnswers":["Electric Watch","Fingerprint scanner","Microwave"],"question":"Which Gadget Was Invented By Douglas Englebart In 1964","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Equals","incorrectAnswers":["Blind Willie Johnson","Ike and Tina Turner","Metallica"],"question":"Which artist first recorded 'Police on My Back', which was later covered by The Clash?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Jim Thorpe","incorrectAnswers":["Bob Mathias","Bruce Jenner","Ashton Eaton"],"question":"Who won the decathlon with a then-record 8,412 points in the 1912 Olympics?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1666","incorrectAnswers":["1366","1466","1566"],"question":"In What Year Did The Great Fire Of London Occur?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"René Descartes","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Jacques Rousseau","Epictetus","Socrates"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'I think therefore I am' ('Cogito, ergo sum')?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Haricot","incorrectAnswers":["Cannelini","Butter","Borlotti"],"question":"Which Type Of Beans Are Used To Make Baked Beans?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'The Dark Side of the Moon'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Uruguay","incorrectAnswers":["France","Brazil","Argentina"],"question":"Which country won the 1930 FIFA World Cup, hosted in Uruguay?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Turnip","incorrectAnswers":["Cherry","Plum","Lúcuma"],"question":"Which of these foods is not a fruit?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Christoph Waltz","incorrectAnswers":["Alan Arkin","Robert De Niro","Philip Seymour Hoffman"],"question":"Who won the 2012 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor for playing the role of Dr. King Schultz in Django Unchained?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Western Samoa ","incorrectAnswers":["Fiji","Japan","New Caledonia"],"question":"Which Pacific Nation Gained Independence From New Zealand In 1962","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Yalta","incorrectAnswers":["Dresden","Maastricht","Versailles"],"question":"Where did Churchill, Roosevelt and Stalin meet in 1945?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Penélope Cruz","incorrectAnswers":["Amy Adams","Uma Thurman","Cameron Diaz"],"question":"Which actress has featured in films including Volver and All About My Mother?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jonah Hill","incorrectAnswers":["Javier Bardem","Hugo Weaving","Warwick Davis"],"question":"Which actor has appeared in both Django Unchained and Moneyball?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Trivial Pursuit","incorrectAnswers":["Kerplunk","Settlers of Catan","Yahtzee!"],"question":"What board game, introduced in the eighties, features six categories of questions and little pie shaped pieces you have to collect?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Eswatini is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Mauritius is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Matrix","incorrectAnswers":["Blade Runner","Terminator 2: Judgment Day","Star Trek: First Contact"],"question":"Which futuristic 1999 film did Will Smith famously turn down for the lead role, later praising Keanu Reeves for his performance?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Stratosphere","incorrectAnswers":["Exosphere","Thermosphere","Mesosphere"],"question":"What is the troposphere immediately lower than?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the studio album 'Anti'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kenneth Branagh","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Ironside","Luke Evans","Tom Waits"],"question":"Which actor has played roles in films including Murder on the Orient Express and Dunkirk?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Eight","incorrectAnswers":["Three","Two","Seven"],"question":"What does the word 'oito' mean in Portuguese?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Energizer","incorrectAnswers":["Red Cross","IBM","FedEx"],"question":"'Keeps going and going and going' is a slogan associated with which brand?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"a-ha","incorrectAnswers":["Biz Markie","Haddaway","Bobby McFerrin"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1985 with Take on Me?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Washington D.C. ","incorrectAnswers":["Budapest","Freetown","New Delhi"],"question":"Which capital city stands on the Potomac River?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Mary Queen Of Scots","incorrectAnswers":["Elizabeth I","Victoria","Jane Seymour"],"question":"Who was the mother of James I of England?","difficulty":"hard"},